

Junior Kaningini L.

Machine Learning Engineer and Computer Security Expert

- ▶ Kinsakala 01/Ngaliema/Kinshasa
- ▶ Email: nkaningini@aimsammi.org
- Tel: +243817138062 +243817138062 (WhatsApp)
- GitHub
- LinkedIn
- Web page

Skills

HTML+CSS+PHP+JS 9+ Years Python, Java, C#, VB 8+ Years Pytorch, Tensoflow 5+ Years Cyber security 6+ Years. **Network Management** 8+ Years. 8+ Years. System Linux, Windows 8+ Years. Web development **Machine Learning** 4+ Year. **Blockchain** 5+ Years. Internet of things 5+ Years. Cloud computing 5+ Years. 5+ Years. Latex

Langues

| Français | ++++ |
|----------|------|
| Anglais | +++ |
| Swahili | ++++ |
| Lingala | ++++ |

Summary

I am a passionate researcher in machine learning and computer security. I have a strong background in data science, machine learning and computer security. In addition to computer security and machine learning, I am also a web developer and have a strong background in network and operating system administration on Linux and Windows. I have knowledge in human resources management, project management and administration, public management. I am able to adapt to a new environment and have analytical and problem solving skills.

Experience

Data Scientist | AGINET

IT Company

March 2023 - Now

My role is to build systems for collecting and analyzing the company's data. I am also responsible for the design, development and deployment of intelligent systems capable of solving complex problems and making automated decisions, etc.

Assistant of IT Manager | AIMS-Senegal

Feb 2021 - August 2021

African Institute for Mathematical Sciences

As an assistant to the IT Manager, I had to design and implement a management application for the AIMS-SENEGAL Center including several functionalities such as data analysis, information system security, financial management, academic management, etc..

Trainee at AIMS-SENEGAL

October 2020-Feb 2021

African Institute for Mathematical Sciences

The internship was in the IT department where I was the assistant of the IT Manager. During the internship, I had to develop a management application for the AIMS SENGAL center. Network and operating system administration were also part of my tasks..

Founder of the company JKnTech

March 2019 -Now

Kinshasa / Democratic Repuplic of Congo

JKnTech is a multi-sector technology company operating in several fields of information technology.

National president of PPJ | DRC

September 2015 - Now

Youth Popular Podium

PPJ is a platform for young people with several objectives in different fields including education, the environment, agriculture, new information technology, etc. I coordinate all activities done by the organization.

Assistant at UNIKIN | DRC

Juin 2017 - Now

University of Kinshasa in DRC

My tasks included: Computer Security, Operating System, Computer Network, Computer Architecture, Architecture of Teleinformatic Systems, Operating System Design, etc...

Trainer at IT Department of

Sept 2016- March 2017

The Ministry of Finance / KINSHASA (DRC)

With the task of managing the payroll application

Education

31 Jan 2022 - 30 Jun 2023

Master in Artificial Intelligence (AMMI)

African Institute of Mathematical Sciences (AIMS-Senegal)

Option: Machine Learning

Sept 2019 - Feb 2021

Master in Mathematical Science

African Institute of Mathematical Sciences (AIMS-Senegal)

Option: Computer Security

September 2014 - Sept 2016

Bachelor's degree in Mathematic and Computer Science

University of Kinshasa / DRC

Option: Computer Engineering

September 2011 - Sept 2014

Graduate diploma in Science

University of Kinshasa / DRC

July 2010

State diploma in Mathematic and Physics

Kalumbwa Institute / DRC / South Kivu / Shabunda

Interests

- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- Operational Research
- IBM Cloud, Coursera
- Travel
- Music
- Sport: Soccer, running

Certificates

October 2022 : Supervised Machine Learning: Regression and Classification

May 2022:Certified in Cybersecurity Intro May 2022: Certified in Machine Learning V2

July 2021: Python for Data Science, Al and Development

Certified on Responsive Web Design August 2020: Certified on Blockchain Basics August 2020: Certified on Cryptography August 2020:

August 2020: Certified on HTML, CSS, and Javascript for Web Developers

August 2020: Certified on Hardware Security

July 2020: Hardware Security on the Building a Google Firebase Web Application

July 2020: Introduction to the Internet of Things and Embedded Systems

July 2020: Certified on the Usable Security

Jun 2020: Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure May 2020:Certified on the Blockchain and Cryptocurrency Explained Certified on the Industrial IoT on Google Cloud Platform May 2020: Certified on Blockchain: Foundations and Use Cases APRIL 2020 : April 2020 : Certified on Build the Voting Application using Blockchain

April 2020: Certified on Cyber Threats and Attack Vectors

April 2020: Certified on Python /IBM

April 2020 : Certified on Enterprise System Management and Security

March 2020: Certified on Identify and Investigate Cybersecurity Threats /IBM

February 2020: Certified on Cloud Computing /IBM Certified on Cyber Security /IBM February 2020:

February 2020: Certified on Internet of Things (IoT) /IBM

January 2020 : Certified on Blockchain Intro /IBM May 2018: Certified on Linux System Administration

Ref: Campus Numérique Fraconcophone(DRC/KINSHASA)

February 2018: Certified on Linux Network administration

Ref: Campus Numérique Fraconcophone(DRC/KINSHASA)

March 2016: Interface-Homme-Machine (IHM)

Conferences

August 2022: Cryptography and Number Theory/CIMPA Senegal

Jun 2022: A mathematical modelling perspective on ecology, biodiversity August 2021: Summer School on Quantum Thermodynamics/Zurich University

May 2018: Algorithmic arithmetic and cryptography/CIMPA-DRC

References

Professor Mouhamed Moustapha Fall

Position: President of AIMS Senegal

EMAIL: mouhamed.m.fall@aims-senegal.org

Professor Pierre Kafunda Katalay

Position: University of KINSHASA kafundakatalay@gmail.com EMAIL:

Mouhamed Lamine Diallo

Position: IT Manager of AIMS-Senegal EMAIL: mldiallo@aims-senegal.org